Okay, so hello everyone in this video, we are going to work with our message model.js. Okay, so we are going to like we are making a chat app, right?
So it is going to have some model for messaging like when we are going to text from person to person.
So there's a user to user reference also and we are going to transmit the like text or image or whatever.
So for that one, we are going to make one model. So for this, we are going to do the for the same process.
So import mongoose from mongoose. Okay, so now what we are going to do is a const message schema.
Okay, so message schema equal to same like as what we have done with this user model.js.
Okay, so new mongoose dot schema, we are going to make a schema for the message and for that one, what will we have?
We have the center ID. Okay, so for the sender ID. Let's take let's make this one as object type.
So sender ID. So the sender ID would have the type. So the type would be mongoose mongoose dot schema dot types dot object ID.
Okay, so this is actually referring to one user. So sender would be a user.
That's why we are using this reference as user and the required would be true.
Since in this model, there would be a sender and a receiver. So the required would be true.
And after this, we are going to make another object. So for this one would be the receiver ID.
Okay, so REC EIVR receiver ID. And same thing, the type would be let's copy paste these two.
So type would be mongoose dot, same thing mongoose dot schema dot type dot object ID.
In the reference would be the user. Then the required would be true as well.
So required true since we also required the receiver, right?
So the receiver and the user both can message each other with either text or image or both at the same time.
So for that, I'm going to take this text object and this text object that type would be string.
So it would be string type and similarly we can take another one that would be image.
So image for this image, same thing we can assign. The type would be the type string.
Save this and now the last thing which we need to do is we need to update the timestamps.
So timestamps would be true, timestamps is true and now let's export default
mongoose dot model and with this one, we will export this as message, comma message schema.
So now we have exported this message schema.
In the routes folder here, we are going to make this as message wait a second.
So in the routes folder, let's create one file which is called as message routes.
So we are also going to use the message routes right. So message routes.js and then import
express from express as usual. So we are going to express import this express module and now
what we are going to do is for this route, const route equal to express dot router.
We are going to use express router to route to this, and this one also right. So now export
default route, we are going to export default this route. So and now we are going to
just in this app.js, we are going to just configure these message routes right.
So what we are going to do is first we have to import this, so let's import import.
Okay, so the not message, it's actually route from routes last message routes.js.
So we have imported this now app.use.
We are going to just take this. So it would be slash API slash message, it is going to the message
and now message route. Okay.
Well, let's save this.
Oh, it's message route is not defined. Okay. So I think there's some issue. So we have imported
this as route. We should import this as message message route.
Okay, now it's running fine.
Now in the next video, we are going to see how to configure all this for this as a controller.